<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on A Morsel Of Code</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on A Morsel Of Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:22:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 4 Machine Learning Multiple Regression</title>
      <link>/2019/02/02/part-4-ml-multiple-linear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 15:22:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/02/02/part-4-ml-multiple-linear-regression/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we learnt about a P-Value, a prerequisite for learning Multiple Linear Regression.
Business Problem: In this series, we will take a look at a dataset of 50 startup companies. A venture capitalist has hired you as a data scientist and wants you to help him select which type of company he should invest so that he can make the most profit. You need to review spending on R&amp;amp;D, Admin cost, marketing cost and location to make the decision</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 3 Machine Learning Understanding P Value</title>
      <link>/2019/01/27/part-3-ml-understanding-p-value/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 17:27:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/27/part-3-ml-understanding-p-value/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, we learnt about Simple Linear regression. I wanted to start this section with multiple linear regression tutorial but as I was going over the content on the template to run create the regression model, I felt that we need understand P-Value concept before we move ahead.
So what is P-Value ?
Before I bore you with stats definition of the P-Value. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with something simple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 2 Machine Learning Simplelinear Regression</title>
      <link>/2019/01/22/part-2-ml-simplelinear-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 21:41:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/22/part-2-ml-simplelinear-regression/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post we learned about data pre-processing. In this post we will review the simplest algorithm - Simple Linear Regression.
Business Problem: In this series, we are going to learn about Simple Linear Regression. We will review a data set about Salary and Experience in age. As a data scientist, your job is to help the HR department predict the salary of a person based on his years of experience if he or she accepts the job offer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Part 1 Machine Learning Data Preprocessing</title>
      <link>/2019/01/21/part-1-ml-data-preprocessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:35:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/01/21/part-1-ml-data-preprocessing/</guid>
      <description>This is the first of many series on machine learning.
Get the Dataset  Download the following zip files
 Jupyter Notebook &amp;amp; images Data  Unzip the folder and copy Files and Data under folder location Machine Learning A-Z Template Folder\Part 1 - Data Preprocessing
Review the dataset   The above dataset shows Country, Age, Salary and Purchased. The field that we need to research is called Dependent field and others are called Independent Field</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>